I should've known that you would be here, Professor McGonagall.
我早该想到会在这壬见到
Good evening, Professor Dumbledore.
了晚安，好不利多教授
Are the rumors true, Albus?
传并是真的吗，阿不思?
I'm afraid so, professor. The good and the bad.
我想是真的，教授 有好消息，也有壤消息
-And the boy? -Hagrid is bringing him.
-那个孩子呢? -海格会把他带到这儿来
Is it wise to trust Hagrid with something so important?
你党得这广做明智吗? 把这种大事交给海格去闪?
Professor, 1 would trust Hagrid with my life.
教授，我可以把自己的命 交到海格手中
Professor Dumbledore, sir. Professor McGonagall.
部不利多教授
-No problems, I trust, Hagrid? -No, sir.
-没遇到什么麻烦吧，海格? -没有，先生
Little tyke fell asleep as we were flying over Bristol.
小像伙一屡到布里斯托就睡了
Try not to wake him.
小心，别吵醒他
There you go.
你看
Do you really think it's safe, leaving him with these people?
你觉得把他交给这些人好吗?
I've watched them all day. They're the worst sort of Muggles.
我在这里观察了一整天 真是一群扰可救本的太太
-They really are-- -The only family he has.
-他们真的是… -他在世上唯一的亲人
He'll be famous. Every child in our world will know his name.
这孩子将来会非常有名，我们世界中的 每个孩子都会知道他的名字
Exactly.
完全正确
He's far better off growing up away from all of that.
最好是让他成长时速和克这一切
Until he’s ready.
等他能锡接受的时候再告诉他
There, there, Hagrid. It's not really goodbye, after all.
好了，好了，海格 又不是再也见不到面
Good luck...
祝你好运
...Harry Potter.
哈利波特
Up. Get up!
起来 ! 起床嗓 !
Now!
快呀 !
Wake up, cousin! We're going to the zoo!
起来了，表弟 ! 要去动物园唾 !
-Here he comes, the birthday boy. -Happy birthday, son.
-吗，我们的小表星来了 -生日快乐，儿子
Cook breakfast. And try not to burn anything.
快去者早餐，不准烧焦东西
-Yes, Aunt Petunia. -l want everything to be perfect...
-是，佩妮阿姨 -我希望今天一切顺心
...for my Dudley's special day!
这可是我们过力的大日子
-Hurry up! Bring my coffee, boy. -Yes, Uncle Vernon.
-快呀 ! 给我咖啡，小子 -是，威农姨丈
Aren't they wonderful, darling?
是不是很棒呀，亲过的?
-How many are there? -36. Counted them myself.
-一共有效个? -三十六个，我自己数的
36?! But last year I had 37!
三十六个?但去年有三十七个 !
-But some are bigger than last year's. -I don't care!
-但有些礼物比去年的大一点呀 -我管它有多大
This is what we're going to do.
好，好，待会儿我们一出去
We're going to buy you two hew presents. How's that, pumpkin?
就再去替你买琴个新礼物 好不好呀，小乎冬?
It should be a lovely day at the zoo. I'm really looking forward to it.
要去动物园了 一定可以玩得很开心，真期待
I'm warning you now, boy.
我警告你，小子
Any funny business, any at all...
要是有任何怪事发生 只要有一点点的怪事
...and you won't have any meals for a week.
你就一个礼拜不准吃饭
Get in.
上车
Make it move.
叫炖支嘛
Move!
支呀 !
-Move! -He's asleep!
-快动呀 ! -物在睡觉
He's boring.
怨无聊死了
Sorry about him.
对不起
He doesn't understand what it's like, lying there...
他不了解你的感觉 像这样一天又一天地躺在这儿
... watching people press their ugly faces in on you.
看人们硬把醒脸贴到你面前
Can you hear me?
你了得懂我的话?
It's just, I've never talked to a snake before.
只是… 我以前从来没跟蛇讲过话
Do you...?
你…
Do you talk to people often?
我是说，你常跟人说话吧?
You're from Burma, aren't you? Was it nice there?
你是从缅甸来的，对吧? 那儿是不是很美?
Do you miss your family?
你想家吗?
I see. That's me as well. I never knew my parents either.
我仅了“，我也一样 我没见过我的父母
Mummy, Dad, you won't believe what this snake is doing!
妈!爸! 你绝对想不到这焦蛇在干嘛
Thanks.
谢了
Anytime.
别客气
Snake!
有蛇!
Mum! Mummy! Help me!
妈，娅味，救救我
My darling boy! How did you get in there?
宝贝儿子，你是怎广进去的?
Who did this? How did you get in there? Is there a snake?
我的天哪，你是怎订进去的? 那是一焦蛇吗?
It's all right, sweetheart. We'll get you out of these cold clothes.
没事的，小甜心 我们会帮你把这混冷的衣服有辽掉
-What happened? -l swear, I don't know!
-这是怎庆回事? -我发效我真的不晓得
The glass was there and then it was gone, like magic.
玻璃忽然消失了 就像演魔和本一样
There's no such thing as magic.
世上根本就没有魔法
Marge is ill. Ate a funny whelk.
玛姬病了，吃了个怪油螺
-Dad, look! Harry's got a letter! -It's mine!
-爸，你看 ! 哈利有一封信 -那是我的
Yours? Who'd be writing to you?
你的? 谁会窟信给你啊?
No more mail through this letterbox.
这样就不能再往信箱里投信了
Have a lovely day at the office, dear.
祝你上班愉快，亲过的
Shoo! Go on.
快滚
Fine day, Sunday.
星期天真是个好日子
In my opinion, best day of the week. Why is that, Dudley?
我认为是一星期中最棒的一天 这是什么原因，速力?
-Because there's no post on Sundays? -Right you are, Harry!
-因为星期天不送信 ? -答对了，哈利
No post on Sunday.
星期天不送信
No blasted letters today! No, sir.
今天没有诗灰的信 ! 没有 !
Not one single bloody letter. Not one!
没有一封该死的信，完全没有
No, sir, not one blasted, miserable--
没有，没有一封装屡、可恶…
Make it stop, please!
叫它停下来，拜证
Stop it!
快停 !
Mummy, what's happening?
妈，这是怎太一回事?
Give me that! Give me that letter!
把它给我 ! 把信给我 !
Get off!
放手 !
They're my letters! Let go of me!
这是我的信，放并我 !
That's it! We're going away!
金了，我们走吧
Far away, where they can't find us!
走得下下的，让他们找不到
Daddy's gone mad, hasn't he?
爸爸发瘦了，是不是?
Make a wish, Harry.
许个愿吧“，哈利
Who's there?
什么人?
Sorry about that.
抱歉
I demand that you leave at once. You are breaking and entering.
我要你立刻疮开 你这是非法侵入民宅
Dry up, Dursley, you great prune.
少喔嗪，德思礼，你这大策伯
Il haven't seen you since you was a baby, Harry.
上回我看到你的时候 你还是个贞儿，哈利
You're a bit more along than I expected. Particularly in the middle.
你泌头比我想的大多了 而且肚子还这广凸
I'm not Harry.
我又不是喻利
-lam. -Well, of course you are.
-我才是 -嗯，这才对嘛
Got something for you.
我这儿有个东西要送你
Afraid I sat on it, but Il imagine it'll taste fine just the same.
好像不小心被我压到了 不过味道是不会伙的
Baked it myself, words and all.
全都是我自己烤的，自己做的哨
Thank you.
谢谢你
It's not every day your young man turns 11, is it?
一草子就只有这麻一次 你现在满十一成唆
Excuse me, but who are you?
对不起，可是你到底是谁呀?
Rubeus Hagrid, Keeper of Keys and Grounds at Hogwarts.
海格，在霍格革兹揽任 欠是管理员与猎场看守人
-Of course, you know about Hogwarts. -Sorry, no.
-你总该晓得霍格革兹吧 -抱歉，不晓得
Didn't you ever wonder where your mum and dad learned it all?
不晓得 ? 我的天哪，哈利 没想过你爸妈是怎订学会的?
Learned what?
学会什么?
You're a wizard, Harry.
你是一个巫师，哈利
-I'm a what? -A wizard.
-我是一个什么? -一个巫师
A good one, I'd wager, once you're trained up.
只要再受点训练 你一定会变成非常属害的巫师
No, you've made a mistake. I mean...
不，我想你弄错了 我是说…
...[ can't be a wizard.
我不可能是巫师啊
I mean, I'm just Harry. Just Harry.
我是说，我只是哈利，我只是哈利
Well, Just Harry, did you ever make anything happen?
好吧“，哈利 你从来没发生过任何怪事吗?
Anything you couldn't explain, when you were angry or scared?
在你生气害怕的时候 没出现什么搞不懂的怪事吗?
"Dear Mr. Potter, We are pleased to accept you...
亲党的波特先生 我们很沫幸能在此通知你
...at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.”
你已获准进入 堆格鞋兹魔法与巫术学院就读
He will not be going! We swore we'd put a stop to all this rubbish.
我不准他去 我发将要禁止这类的蔷唐怪事
You knew? You knew all along and you never told me?
你早就知道了? 你们知道分不告诉我9
Of course we knew. How could you not be?
想也知道你会是什么德行
My perfect sister being who she was.
看看我那完美的好妹妹
My mother and father were so proud the day she got her letter.
她收到信时，和爸杂简直乐牌了
"We have a witch in the family. Isn't it wonderful?”
家里出了个女巫，好棒喃
l was the only one to see her for what she was.
就只有我能看清她的真面目
A freak!
她是一个怪胎
Then she met that Potter, and then she had you...
然后她嫁给那个波特，生了你
...and I knew you would be the same. Just as strange, just as abnormal.
我就知道你会和他们一样奇怪 一样不正常
And then she got herself blown up, and we got landed with you.
然后呢，她就让自己给炸死了 所以我们就只好收留你
Blown up? You told me my parents died in a car crash.
炸死? 你说他们是出车褐死的
A car crash? A car crash killed Lily and James Potter?
车神 ? 车褐哪伤得了莉莉 和詹姆波特?
-We had to say something. -It's an outrage! A scandal!
-我们总得说个理由 -这是一种侮辱，一稳氏诗
He'll not be going.
他不能去
A great Muggle like you is going to stop him?
你以为像你这种超级大有麻扑 阻止得了他吗?
Muggle?
朗瓜?
Non-magic folk. This boy's had his name down since he were born.
就是不会魔法的父伏 他一出生就列入学生名册了
He's going to the finest school of witchcraft and wizardry.
他要去的是世上最棒的魔法巫酝学校
He'll be under the finest headmaster Hogwarts has seen, Albus Dumbledore.
而且膛有有史以来最棒的校长 阿不思必不利多
I will not pay to have a crackpot old fool teach him magic tricks.
休想要我花一文发 让个瘦冲老傻瓜来教他变魔征
Never insult Albus Dumbledore...
不准在我面前…
..in front of me.
侮辱如不利多
I'd appreciate it if you didn't tell anyone at Hogwarts about that.
你可千蕊别告诉霍格革兹的人 我会感激你的
-'m not allowed to do magic. -Okay.
-照规定我是不能使用魔法的 -好
We're a bit behind schedule. Best be off.
进度有点落后了，我们该走唆
Unless you'd rather stay, of course.
难不成你还想待在这儿
"All students must be equipped with...
所有学生都必须准备…
...one standard size 2 pewter cauldron...
一个标准尺寸的白铅大俭
...and may bring, if they desire, either an owl, a cat or a toad.”
可自由揣带 一焦和猎头魔，猫，或是唉叭
Can we find all this in London?
在伦敦能把东西都买蛮吗?
If you know where to go.
只要你知道门路就可以
Ah, Hagrid! The usual, I presume?
啊，海格，老样子对吧?
No, thanks, Tom. I'm on official Hogwarts business.
不，谢了，汤姆 我正在替霍格芋兹办事
Just helping Harry buy his school supplies.
带小哈利去买学校要用的东西
Bless my soul. It's Harry Potter!
上帝保佑我 他是哈利波特!
Welcome back, Mr. Potter. Welcome back.
坎迎回来，波特先生 坎迎回来
Doris Crockford. I can't believe I'm meeting you at last.
我是桃莉 真不敢相信我终於见到你了
Harry Potter. Can't tell you how pleased I am to meet you.
哈利波特 见到你真说不出有多高届
Hello, professor. I didn’t see you.
哈唾，教授，刚才没看到你
Professor Quirrell will be your Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher.
这位是挛若教授 堆格村兹的黑魔法防集街老师
Oh, nice to meet you.
喔，真高典见到你
Fearfully fascinating subject.
这门课迷人得很
Not that you need it, eh, Potter?
但你已经不用学了，对吧?
Yes, well, must be going now. Lots to buy.
现在得上路了，好多东西要圈
Goodbye.
再见
-See, Harry? You're famous. -But why am I famous?
-了瞧，哈利，你有名得很 -但我为什么会出名呢?
All those people, how is it they know who I am?
那些人为什么全都认识我?
I'm not sure I'm the right person to tell you that.
我不晓得这事由我来告诉你 究竟合不合通
Welcome, Harry, to Diagon Alley.
炊迎来到斜角埠，哈利
Here, you get your quills and ink.
这儿可以买到羽毛笔和墨水
Over there, all your bits and bobs for doing wizardry.
那晃是次各式各样的魔法玩意
It's a world-class racing broom.
世界级的比赛用郝天返斋
Look at it! The new Nimbus 2000!
哇，快看 ! 最新型的光输雨千
It's the fastest model yet.
目前最快的型号
But how am I to pay for all this? I haven't any money.
但是我哪买得起这些东西?9 我束一毛钱也没有
There's your money. Gringotts, the wizard bank.
你的钱在那里 古起关，巫师银行
Ain't no safer place, not one. Except perhaps Hogwarts.
(十直阅银行)
Hagrid, what exactly are these things?
海格，那是什么怪物呀?
They're goblins. Clever as they come, but not the most friendly of beasts.
那就是妖精啊 妖精陷明得很，但可不太友善
Best stay close.
最好是紧跟在我身站
Mr. Harry Potter wishes to make a withdrawal.
哈利波特先生想要提袋
And does Mr. Harry Potter have his key?
哈利波特先生有带欠王吗?
Wait a minute. Got it here somewhere.
等等，就在身上
Ha! There's the little devil.
小鬼难强
And there’s something else as well.
还有另一件事
Professor Dumbledore gave me this.
这是好不利多教授交给我的
It's about You-Know-What in vault you-know-which.
就是那个金库里的那个东西
Very well.
好的
Vault 687.
六百人十七号地下人金亩
Lamp, please.
请把炬给我
Key, please.
给是
Did you think your parents would leave you with nothing?
你以为你爸杂什么也没留给你?
-Vault 713. -What's in there, Hagrid?
-七百十三号地下金库 -里面放了什么东西，海格?
Can't tell you. Hogwarts business. Very secret.
这我可不能告诉你 那是霍格革兹的最高机密
Stand back.
退复
Best not to mention this to anyone.
最好别跟任何人提起这回事
I still need a wand.
我还需要一根魔杖
A wand? You want Ollivanders. There ain't no place better.
魔杖? 好，去奥利凡德吧 那是最棒的地方
Hello?
哈唾?
I wondered when I'd be seeing you, Mr. Potter.
我才在想什么时候会见到你 波特先生
It seems only yesterday...
那好像是昨天才发生的事
...that your mother and father were in here buying their first wands.
你父母上人这儿来买第一根魔杖
Here we are.
我们试试这个
Give it a wave.
好，挥挥看吧
Apparently not.
显然不行
Perhaps...
也许…
... this.
这个可以
No, no, definitely not. No matter.
不行，不行，绝对不行 没关俐
Curious.
真稀奇
Very curious.
真的是非常稀奇
Sorry, but what's curious?
对不起，你为什么觉得稀奇?
l remember every wand I've ever sold, Mr. Potter.
我记得我焉出的每一根魔杖 波特先生
It so happens that the phoenix...
浅巧的是…
...whose tail feather resides in your wand, gave another feather.
给了你魔杖一根尾羽的那焦凤凰 另外还有一根尾区给了…
Just one other.
另外一根魔杖
It is curious that you should be destined for this wand...
而稀奇的是 你注定就要使用这根魔杖
...when its brother gave you that scar.
因为另一根魔杖的主人 在你领对留下了那道疤痕
And who owned that wand?
那根魔杖的主人是谁?
We do not speak his name.
他的名字我们不能说
The wand chooses the wizard, Mr. Potter.
是魔杖来选择巫师的，波特先生
It's not always clear why.
原因向来都不清楚
But I think it is clear...
但我想这区很清楚…
...that we can expect great things from you.
你未来会有了不起的成就
After all, He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named...
不管怎入说 那个不能说出名字的人…
...did great things.
做了些很了不起的事
Terrible...
路然可怕…
... yes, but great.
但还是很了不起
Harry! Harry!
哈利，哈利
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
You all right, Harry? You seem very quiet.
你没事吧 ? 怎庆都不咏声呢?
He killed my parents, didn't he? The one who gave me this.
是他角了我的父母，对不对 ? 就是那个害我留下这道净的人
You know, Hagrid. 1 know you do.
你知道的，海格，你一定知道
First, and understand this because it's very important:
你得先了解一件事 因为这非常重要
Not all wizards are good.
巫师范不一定都是好人
Some of them go bad. A few years ago...
有些巫师会变球 厂年前…
...there was a wizard who went as bad as you can go. His name was V--
有个巫师简直壤到骨子里去了 他的名字叫佛…
-His name was V-- -Maybe if you wrote it down?
-他的名字叫佛… -还是你用写的好了?
No, I can't spell it.
不行，这字我不会拼
-All right, Voldemort. -Voldemort?
-好吧，佛地魔 -佛地魔?
It was dark times, Harry.
那真是一段可怕的日子，哈利
Voldemort started to gather some followers.
佛地魔那时聚集了一批朴牙
Brought them over to the Dark Side.
说动他们投靠黑暗势力
Anyone that stood up to him ended up dead.
反抗他的人全都被角光
Your parents fought against him.
你爸妈勇敢跟他对抗
But nobody lived once he decided to kill them.
但只要是他添定要角的人 没一个能逃遇他的毒手
Nobody, not one.
没有，一个也没有
Except you.
只有你例外
Me? Voldemort tried to kill me?
我?佛地魔想角我?
Yes. That ain't no ordinary cut on your forehead, Harry.
没错，你额头上的疤很不寻常
A mark like that only comes from being touched by a curse, an evil curse.
只有诅咒才会留下那样的痕中 而且是个敌码的诅咒
What happened to V--? To You-Know-Who?
那个人和后来怎庆样 ?
Well, some say he died.
这个嘛，有人说他死了…
Codswallop, in my opinion.
但依我看是胡说八道
Nope, I reckon he’s out there still...
不，我想他和膛躲在某个地方
...too tired to carry on.
虚弱得无法抬取行动
But one thing's certain. Something about you stumped him that night.
但有件事倒是可以确定 你那晚让他栽了个大跟斗
That's why you're famous. That's why everybody knows your name.
所以你才会这庆有名 大家才会全都认识你
You're the boy who lived.
你可是唯一活下来的男孩
What are you looking at?
你们在看什么 ?
Blimey, is that the time?
哎呀，现在站点啦?
I'm gonna have to leave you. Dumbledore will be wanting his--
对不起，哈利，我得走了 好不利多等著要拿他的…
Well, he'll be wanting to see me. Your train leaves in 10 minutes.
好了，他等著要见我 你的火车再十分镀就要天了
Here's your ticket. Stick to your ticket, that's very important.
这是你的车标 把车票收好，这很重要
"Platform 9 3’4"?
九又四分之三月台?
But, Hagrid, there must be a mistake. This says platform 9 3(4.
但是，海格，这一定弄错了 上面窟九又四分之三月台
There's no such thing, is there?
哪有这种月台呀?
Sorry.
抱歉
Excuse me. Excuse me.
对不起，对不起
On your left.
从左下通道穿台去
Can you tell me where I might find platform 9 34?
和对不起，先生 九又四分之三月台在哪儿2?
Think you're being funny, do you?
你故意装傻整我天心吗?
It's the same every year, packed with Muggles.
每年都一样，撞满了麻扑
-Muggles? -Platform 9 3’4, this way.
-县瓜? -九又四分之三月台，这超走
All right, Percy, you first.
好，派西，你先走
Fred, you next.
弗雷，你下一个
-He's not Fred, I am. -You call yourself our mother?
-他不是弗雷，我才是 -逮好意思自称母亲吗?
I'm sorry, George.
对不起，在治
I'm only joking. I am Fred.
天玩笑的啦，我是弗雷
Excuse me.
对不起
Could you tell me how to...?
能不能请你告诉我…
How to get onto the platform? Not to worry, dear.
要怎样去月台吗? 放心，没问题的，厅党的
It's Ron's first time to Hogwarts as well.
柴思也是第一次去埠格鞋兹
All you do is walk straight at the wall between platforms 9 and 10.
现在你只要往第九和第十月台 中间那道凋，直接走过去就行了
-Best to run if you're nervous. -Good luck.
-要是紧张的话，最好用小跑步 -祝你好有运
Excuse me. Do you mind? Everywhere else is full.
对不起，我可以坐吗? 其他车麻都满了
Not at all.
坐啊
I'm Ron, by the way. Ron Weasley.
对了，我叫沫思 沫思本斯理
I'm Harry. Harry Potter.
我叫哈利，哈利波特
So it's true!
所以是真的唾 ?
I mean, do you really have the...?
我是说，你真的有…
-The what? -The scar?
-有什么? -那道疤?
Wicked!
真炫 !
-Anything off the trolley, dears? -No, thanks. I'm all set.
-要不要买点儿东西吃呀? -不，谢了，我自己有带吃的
We'll take the lot.
我全部都要
-Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans? -They mean every flavor.
-柏蒂全口味豆子?9 -这表示所有口味都有
There's chocolate and peppermint and also...
有巧克力和薄荷口味，了志有…
... spinach, liver and tripe.
菠菜、肝腑，还有牛肚
George sweared he got a booger-flavored one once.
奇治有次还吃到鼻尿口味的
-Are they real frogs? -It's a spell. You want the cards.
-这该不会是真的青蛙吧 ? -是施了个符只，膛让你搜集卡月
Each pack’'s got a famous witch or wizard. I've got about 500 meself.
每包附一张名巫师或女巫卡片 我已经收集大约五百张了
Watch it!
小心
That's rotten luck. They've only got one good jump in them.
运气真背 它们只有一开始那下跳得最好
-'ve got Dumbledore! -1 got about six of him.
-我拿到好不利多了 -我足足有六引
Hey, he's gone!
嘿，他不见了
You can't expect him to hang around all day, can you?
你不能要他整天都待在那儿吧?
This is Scabbers. Pathetic, isn't he?
这是斑斑 他很可屋，对不对?
A little.
还好啦
Fred gave me a spell to turn him yellow. Want to see?
弗雷教了我一个咒语 可以把怨变成黄色，要看吧?
Yeah.
好啊
Has anyone seen a toad?
有没有人看到一焦唉内?
-A boy named Neville’s lost one. -No.
-奈威的蟾只不见了 -没有
Oh, are you doing magic? Let's see, then.
吗，你在施魔法吗? 让我们瞧一瞧吧
Sunshine, daisies, butter mellow
阳光，雏菊，甜奶油
Turn this stupid, fat rat yellow
将这焦又胖又策老鼠释成黄色
Are you sure that's a real spell? Well, it's not very good, is it?
你确定这是真的响语吗 ? 显然不是很有用，对不对 ?
I've only tried a few simple ones myself...
我也只试过类个简单的咒语
...but they've all worked for me.
但每欢都非常成功
For example:
比方说…
Oculus Reparo.
欧卡拉斯雷培洛
That's better, isn't it?
是不是好了?
Holy cricket, you're Harry Potter!
我的天哪，你是哈利波特!
I'm Hermione Granger. And you are...?
我叫妙杂格茸像 那你是…?
-I'm Ron Weasley. -Pleasure.
-我叫荣因本斯理 -幸会
You two better change into robes. l expect we'll be arriving soon.
你们两个最好超快换上长袍 我们大概快要到了
You've got dirt on your nose. Did you know?
你鼻子上黑黑的，晓不晓得?
Just there.
就在这
Right, then. First years, this way, please!
好，一年级新生 请跟我来
Come on, first years, don't be shy. Come on now, hurry up.
快呀，一年级新生，别害姜 走呀，快点，走呀
-Hello, Harry. -Hi, Hagrid.
-哈吧，哈利 -嘿，海格
Right, then. This way to the boats. Come on now, follow me.
好，走这儿上船 快，跟我来
Wicked.
真炫 !
Welcome to Hogwarts.
炊迎来到埠格鞋兹
Shortly, you'll pass through these doors and join your classmates.
待会儿你们就要走进这局门 跟其他同学玫聚一堂
But before you take your seats, you must be sorted into your houses.
但在你们到餐厅入席之前 必须先杞你们分派学院
They are Gryffindor, Hufflepuff...
学院有葛来分多，赫夫帕夫
...Ravenclaw and Slytherin.
雷文克劳，还有史莱哲林
While you're here, your house will be like your family.
在你们就学期问 学院就像是你们的家庭一样
Your triumphs will earn you points.
你们所表现出色会蔚学院加分
Any rule-breaking and you will lose points.
而这规则会使学院被扣分
At the end of the year, the house with the most points wins the house cup.
学年结束时，积分最高的学院 将会获得学院鼻冠军
Trevor!
吹宣
Sorry.
对不起
The Sorting Ceremony will begin momentarily.
分类仪式马上就要开始了
It's true then, what they're saying on the train.
那是真的吗 火车上的传关果真没错
Harry Potter has come to Hogwarts.
哈利波特到霍格革兹来唾
Harry Potter?
哈利波特
This is Crabbe and Goyle.
这是克拉和高锁
And I'm Malfoy.
我叫马份
Draco Malfoy.
践哥马份
Think my name's funny, do you? I've no need to ask yours.
觉得我名字很好笑是不是?9 我不用癌就知道你是谁
Red hair and a hand-me-down robe? You must be a Weasley.
你想必是卫斯理家的人
You'll find out some wizarding families are better than others.
你马上就会发现，某些巫师家庭 比别人高级些
You don't want to go making friends with the wrong sort.
没人会想跟差盈像伙交朋友
I can help you there.
这方面我可以帮你
I think I can tell the wrong sort for myself, thanks.
我可以看得出是谁比较差副，谢了
We're ready for you now. Follow me.
一切准人备就绪，请跟我来吧
The ceiling isn't real. It's bewitched to look like the night sky.
他们对天花板施了魔法 让它看起来像是夜晚的天空
l read about it in Hogwarts, A History.
我在《霍格革兹一段历史》 这本书上读到过
Will you wait along here, please?
请在这儿等一下
Now, before we begin...
了著，在我们开始之前
...Professor Dumbledore would like to say a few words.
好不利多教授要先说颖句话
I have a few start-of-term notices I wish to announce.
我想向大家宣做 新学期一些必须注意事项
The first years, please note...
一年级新生注意了
...that the Dark Forest is strictly forbidden to all students.
黑和森林绝对禁止学生进入
Also, our caretaker, Mr. Filch, has asked me to remind you...
另外，管理员赤七先生 要我提醒各位
...that the third-floor corridor is out of bounds...
不可踏进三楼右手站走廊
...to everyone who does not wish to die a most painful death.
除非你想七宕流血、痛车惨死
Thank you.
谢谢大家
When I call your name, you will come forth.
当我叫到你的名字 你就走到前面来
I shall place the Sorting Hat on your head...
我会把分类帽戴到你头上
...and you will be sorted into your houses.
替你分派学院
Hermione Granger.
妙对格戎像
Oh, no. Okay, relax.
吗，不，好，放到鼎
Mental, that one, I'm telling you.
我告诉你，那像伙头胶有问题
Right, then. Right.
呵，很好，嗯，好
Okay. Gryffindor!
决定了，葛来分多
Draco Malfoy.
践哥马份
Slytherin!
史莱哲林
Every wizard who went bad was in Slytherin.
所有伙壤的巫师和女巫 全都是史菜哲林出身的
Susan Bones.
艾珊波恩
Harry, what is it?
哈利，怎麻了?
Nothing. Nothing, I'm fine.
没什么，没什么，我没事
Let's see....
让我想想
I know! Hufflepuff!
我知道了，赫夫帕夫
Ronald Weasley.
沫思本斯理
Another Weasley! I know just what to do with you.
又来一个卫斯理 不用想也晓得该把你分到哪
Gryffindor!
萝来分多
Harry Potter.
哈利波特
Difficult, very difficult.
很困准，非常困难
Plenty of courage, I see. Not a bad mind, either.
勇气很足移，心地也不壤
There's talent, oh, yes.
也很有才革，没错
And a thirst to prove yourself.
和一股急著想证明自己的签望
But where to put you?
但我该把你分到哪呢?
Not Slytherin, not Slytherin!
不要史菜哲林，不要史菜哲林
Not Slytherin, eh? Are you sure?
不要史莱哲林 ? 你确定?
You could be great, you know. It's all here, in your head.
你会有了不起的成就 你脑袋里该有的样样不缺
And Slytherin will help you on the way to greatness, no doubt about that.
而史菜哲林可以帮助你登上燃峰 这一点是毫扰疑问的
No? Well, if you're sure.
不要? 好吧，既然你这广确定
Better be...
那就最好是去…
...Gryffindor!
萝来分多
Your attention, please.
请大家注意
Let the feast begin.
宴会开始
I'm half and half.
我是一半一半
Me dad's a Muggle. Mum's a witch.
我爸是脐瓜，我妈是女下
Bit of a nasty shock for him when he found out.
他发现时可真是嘛壤了
Percy, who's that teacher talking to Professor Quirrell?
派西，那个在跟圣若说话的人是谁?
Professor Snape, head of Slytherin house.
那是石内卜教授 史莱哲林的学院千师
-What's he teach? -Potions.
-他教什么科目? -魔药学
But he fancies the Dark Arts. He's been after Quirrell’s job for years.
但他最感机趣的是黑魔法防集征 他早就想接下对车的工作了
Hello! How are you?
哈吐，你好
Welcome to Gryffindor.
炊迎加入和葛来分多
It's the Bloody Baron!
那是血腥男再
Hello, Sir Nicholas. Have a nice summer?
哈唾，尼十拉斯现士 材假遇得还愉快吗?
Dismal. Once again, my request to join the Headless Hunt has been denied.
惨哪，我想参加扰头骑士的狩猎 但是又再度遭到拒绝
I know you. You're Nearly Headless Nick.
我知道你是谁 你是差点没头的尼克
I prefer Sir Nicholas, if you don't mind.
我希望你能叫我尼古拉斯歼士
"Nearly" headless? How can you be nearly headless?
差点没对? 你是怎床个差点没顷法?
Like this.
就像这样
Gryffindors, follow me, please. Keep up. Thank you.
萝来分多学生请跟我走 快跟上啊，谢谢
Ravenclaw, follow me. This way.
雷文克劳学生跟我走，往这超走
This is the most direct path to the dormitories.
这是去寝室最快的一条路
Keep an eye on the staircases. They like to change.
小心楼梯，它们训娄人释来演去
Keep up, please, and follow me. Quickly now, come on. Come on.
请大家跟好，跟我来 现在走快点，快啊
That picture's moving.
那幅首在支
-Look at that one. -I think she fancies you.
-你看那幅媳 -我想她是看上你唆
-Look! -Who's that girl?
-快看 ! -那女的是谁?
Welcome to Hogwarts.
炊迎来到埠格鞋兹
Password?
通关密语 ?
Caput Draconis.
龙湾
Follow me, everyone. Keep up. Quickly, come on.
大家跟我走，快跟上，快
Gather around here.
大家先在这和外集合
Welcome to the Gryffindor common room.
炊迎来到萝来分多交谊廉
Boys’ dormitory is upstairs to the left. Girls, the same on your right.
男生魔室在楼上左逮 女生宕室在右冰
Your belongings have already been brought up.
行李都已经蔡你们送上去了
Made it!
及时直上
Can you imagine the look on old McGonagall's face if we were late?
要是如到的话 堆教授的脸不知道会有多准看
-That was bloody brilliant! -Thank you for that assessment.
-真是太属害了 -吗，谢谢你的评论
It'd be better if I transfigured Mr. Potter and you into a watch.
说不定我党些别的还比较有用 把你或波特先生人变成一焦刍
-Then one of you might be on time. -We got lost.
-这样你们至少有个人不会带到 -我们迷路了
Then perhaps a map? I trust you don't need one to find your seats.
所以该张地图唾? 找位子坐恕不必用到地图吧 ?9
There will be no foolish wand-waving or silly incantations in this class.
这门课不需要你傻呼呼择魔杖 或是噬哩吐噬瞎叭加
As such, I don't expect many of you to appreciate...
所以呢 我坦不期待大多数人能理解…
...the subtle science and exact art that is potion-making.
抽魔药的精密科学与正确技术
However, for those select few...
不过呢，那些出类拔某…
...who possess the predisposition...
扩有特殊天贼的少数人
...[. can teach you how to bewitch the mind...
我可以教你们如何混乱心智
..and ensnare the senses.
和迷惑感官
I can tell you how to bottle fame...
我可以教你们如何赢取名声
... brew glory and even put a stopper in death.
浆者柴耀，甚至阻止死亡
Then again, maybe some of you have come to Hogwarts in possession of abilities...
另外，也许你们有些人在入学时 就已具有非凡的能力…
Mr. Potter.
波特先生
Our new celebrity.
我们这儿的新名人
What would I get if 1 added root of asphodel to an infusion of wormwood?
我若把水包球根粉倒入苦艾汗 会产生什么样的效果?
You don't know? Let’s try again.
你不晓得 ? 我们再试一次
Where would you look if l asked you to find a bezoar?
若是我要你拿一块毛黄石给我 你要到哪找?
I don't know, sir.
我不知道，先生
What is the difference between monkshood and wolfsbane?
那附子和牛遍有什么不同?
Pity.
可屋哪
Clearly, fame isn't everything...
名所显然将不能代表一切
. is it, Mr. Potter?
是不是啊，波特先生?
Eye of rabbit, harp string hum Turn this water into rum
兔子眼，且续蝎费 快将清水变甜酒
What's Seamus trying to do to the water?
西莫干嘛对那杯水叭个不停?
Turn it to rum. Actually managed a weak tea yesterday, before--
想把它党成甜酒 他昨天把水变成了淡茶，在他…
Mail's here.
信来了
Can I borrow this? Thanks.
这可不可以借我看看?谢了
Look, Neville’s got a Remembrall.
你看，奈威收到了一个记收球
I've read about those. The smoke turns red when you've forgotten something.
这我在书上看过，灯要是变红的话 就表示你忘了某件事情
The problem is, 1 can’t remember what I've forgotten.
问题是，我根本就不记得 我忘了什么啊
Somebody broke into Gringotts. Listen.
有人非法间入十起关，你看
"Believed to be the work of Dark wizards or witches...
据说是菜位不知名巫师 或女巫所策划的行动
...Gringotts goblins acknowledge the breach but insist nothing was taken.
古赴阅妖精蓝承认被侵入 但分否认损失任何物品
The vault in question, number 713, had been emptied earlier that same day.”
出事的了7 工3号地下金库 事实上已在当日稍早被提领一空
That's odd. That's the vault Hagrid and I went to.
奇怪了 那就是海格带我去的金库
-Good afternoon, class. -Good afternoon, Madam Hooch.
-同学们午安 -午安，胡奇夫人
Good afternoon, Amanda. Good afternoon.
午安，阿曼达，午安
Welcome to your first flying lesson.
获迎大家来上第一堂屎行课
What are you waiting for? Step up to your broomstick.
你们膛在蓄菇什么 ? 每个人都站到自己抬锅左下
Come on now, hurry up. Stick your hand over the broom and say, "Up."
快呀，快点 把右手伸到抬巡上方说“上来“
Up!
上来
Up. Up!
上来，上来!
With feeling.
要带点感情
Shut up, Harry.
半跑，哈利
Now, once you've got hold of your broom, I want you to mount it.
孤好，抓住抬锅以后 就请你们骑上去
Grip it tight. You don't wanna be sliding off the end.
抓紧一点 免得从和后面滑下来
When I blow my whistle, 1 want you to kick off from the ground, hard.
我一吹口哨 你们大家就用力往上环
Keep your broom steady, hover for a moment...
驯量让抬壳保持稳定 在空中浮一会儿
...then lean forward slightly and touch back down.
然后身子微往前锯 轻轻习回地面
On my whistle. Three, two....
阴我的口哨 三，二…
Mr. Longbottom.
隆巴顿先生
-Mr. Longbottom! -Down, down!
-隆巴顿先生 ! -下去，下去 !
Neville!
奈威 !
Come back down this instant!
立刻给我下来
Everyone out of the way!
大家全都让并
Is he all right?
他没事吧?
Oh, dear, it’s a broken wrist. Poor boy. Come on now, up you get.
吗，亲营的，手腕断了 可情的孩子， 好了，站起来吧
Keep your feet on the ground while I take him to the hospital wing.
在我带这孩子去医访室时 全都给我矢矢站好不准乱飞
Understand? If I see a single broom in the air...
避到没有? 要是让我看到有人悉上天空
...the one riding it will be expelled before they can say Quidditch.
那他还来不及说“魁地奇” 之前 就得给我滚出霍格华兹
Did you see his face?
你们看到他那张大脸了吗?
If he had squeezed this, he'd have remembered to fall on his arse.
要是有捏一捏记疏球 就会记得摔跤时该屁股先著地
Give it here, Malfoy.
把它交出来，马份
No. I'll leave it somewhere for Longbottom to find.
不，我要把它藏在某个地方 让隆巴顿玩玩王实送戏
How about on the roof?
放在屋顶上怎庆样啊?
What's the matter, Potter? Bit beyond your reach?
怎床呢，波特? 拿不到是吧?
Harry, no way! You heard what Madam Hooch said.
哈利，不行 你蜀才也匠到胡奇夫人说的话
Besides, you don't know how to fly.
何涡你根本就不会丧嘛…
What an idiot.
真是个大白半
Give it here or I'll knock you off your broom!
给我，马份 不然我就把你踢下抬壳
Is that so?
是吧?
Have it your way, then.
那你就来拿吧
-Nice going, Harry. -That was wicked, Harry!
-太棒了“，哈利 -堤得好，哈利
Harry Potter!
哈利波特
Follow me.
跟我来
Professor Quirrell, excuse me. Could I borrow Wood for a moment?
对不起，牵若教授 能不能把木适借给我一下?
Yes, of course.
嗯，当然可以
Potter, this is Oliver Wood. Wood, I have found you a Seeker.
波特，这位是奥利佛木透 木延，我共你找到了搜捕手
Have you heard? Harry Potter's the new Gryffindor Seeker.
聘说了吧? 萝来分多的新搜捕手 是哈利波特
l always knew he'd do well.
我早就看出他会有出色的表现
Seeker? But first years hever make the house teams.
搜捕手 ? 但学院代表队 从不收一年级新生
-You must be the youngest player in-- -A century, McGonagall says.
-你钱定是最年反的代表队员…, -一百年来，这是故教授告诉我的
Well done, Harry. Wood's just told us.
干得好，哈利 木透刚才告诉我们了
Fred and George are on the team. Beaters.
弗雷和乔治也是队员 他们是打击手
Our job is to make sure you don't get bloodied up too bad.
我们的任务是 驯量别让你被打得太惨
Can't make any promises. Rough game, Quidditch.
但我们自然不敢提保 魁地奇比赛粗暴得很
But no one's died in years. Someone vanishes occasionally.
但很久没死人了 偶尔会有人消失
But they'll turn up in a month or two.
不过一、丁个月就会再出现
Go on. Quidditch is great. Best game there is, and you'll be great too.
魁地奇很刺激，它是世上最棒的比赛 你也会表现得很棒的
I've never played. What if 1 make a fool of myself?
可是我从来就没打过魁地奇 要是出梗怎庆斩?
You won't make a fool of yourself. It's in your blood.
你不会出醒的啦 你可是家学测源
You never told me your father was a Seeker too.
你没告诉我 你父亲也是搜捕手
I didn't know.
我也不晓得
I'm telling you, it's spooky. She knows more about you than you do.
我告诉你，我党得这很丽怖 你的事她居然知道的比你还多
Who doesn't?
谁都会比我知道的多
What's happening?
怎庆了?
The staircases change, remember?
楼梯会党来党去，记得吧?
-Let’s go this way. -Before the staircase moves again.
-走这下 -免得楼梯又开始乱动
Does anybody feel like we shouldn't be here?
这儿好像不是我们该来的地方
We're not supposed to be here.
我们不能到这壬来呀
This is the third floor. It's forbidden.
这是三楼，这是禁区
Let's go.
我们走吧
-It's Filch's cat! -Run!
-是习七的猫 -快跑 !
Quick, let's hide through that door!
快 ! 躲到那局门和后面
-It's locked! -We're done for!
-门锁上了 -这下我们真的完了
Move over!
让并
Alohomora.
阿洛哈吗啦
Get in.
快进去
Alohomora?
阿洛哈吗啦?
Standard Book of Spells, chapter seven.
《标准咒语》第七章
Anyone here, my sweet?
这儿有人吗，小甜心?
Come on.
走吧
-Filch is gone. -He thinks this door's locked.
-条七走了 -他大概以为这局门是锁上的
-It was locked. -And for good reason.
-本来就是锁上的 -门镇上是有原因的
What are they doing, keeping a thing like that locked up in a school?
他们这些人到底是什么意思 竟然把那征东西关在学校?
Didn't you see what it was standing on?
你没看到怨站在什么东西上面吧?
I wasn't looking at its feet! l was preoccupied with its heads.
我没注意到怨的脚 怨的头就金我看花眼了
Or maybe you didn't notice. There were three!
你说不定没注意到 忽有三个头
It was standing on a trap door. It wasn't there by accident.
凶站在一局活板门上 这代表和忽是有用处的
-It's guarding something. -Guarding something?
-和怨在看守某个东西 -看守某个东西?
That's right. Now, if you two don't mind, I'm going to bed...
没错，你们不介意的话 我要去睡了
...before you come up with another idea to get us killed.
免得你们又想出什么鬼主总 来害我们送命…
Or worse, expelled.
或是更惨的，被学校退学
She needs to sort out her priorities.
她还真分不清事情的到重
Quidditch is easy to understand. Each team has seven players.
你地奇的规则膛炙好懂的 每队有七名球员
Three Chasers, two Beaters, one Keeper and a Seeker. That's you.
三个追跑手，雨个打击手，膛有 看守手和搜捕手，你就是搜捕手
There are three kinds of balls. This one’s called the Quaffle.
钨共有三种球 这叫做快泽
The Chasers handle the Quaffle and try to put it through one of those hoops.
追跑手把快浮传来传去 设法把它射进那三个球框
The Keeper, that’s me, defends the hoops. With me so far?
看守手就是我，负责看守球杠 还跟得上吗?
I think so. What are those?
可以， 那些是什么?
You better take this.
你最好担住这个
Careful now, it’s coming back.
小心，它条回来了
Not bad, Potter. You'd make a fair Beater.
不错嘛，波特 你也可成为优秀的打击手
What was that?
那是什么东西?
Bludger. Nasty little buggers.
搏格，准强的小东西
But you are a Seeker.
但你是一名搜捕手
The only thing 1 want you to worry about is this.
你只要担心这个就行了
The Golden Snitch.
金探子
-l like this ball. -You like it now.
-我喜欢这个球 -你喜欢它唆
Just wait. It's wicked fast and damn near impossible to see.
等著瞧吧 它速度奇快而且神出鬼没
What do I do with it?
那我要做什么 ?
You catch it. Before the other team's Seeker.
赶在别队搜捕手之前抓住它
You catch this, the game's over.
你一抓到它，比赛就会结束
You catch this, Potter, and we win.
你一抓到它，波特 我们就赢了
One of a wizard's most rudimentary skills is levitation...
疆浮是巫师最基本的技巧之一
...or the ability to make objects fly.
这种魔法可以让物体处起来
Do you have your feathers? Good.
大家都拿到巩毛了吗? 很好
Now, don't forget the nice wrist movement we've been practicing.
现在别忘了我们张习过的手腕动作
The swish and flick. Everyone.
挥和弹，大家一起哈
The swish and flick. Good. Oh, and enunciate.
挥和弹，很好 还有发音也很重要
Wingardium Leviosa. Off you go, then.
温咖癌啦唯啊衣 大家开始练习吧
No, stop, stop, stop! You're going to take someone's eye out.
停下来 你会把别人眼睛给蕉里的
Besides, you're saying it wrong. It's Leviosa, not Leviosar.
而且你的发音不正确 应该要强调 “啊”，而不是“荐^
You do it then, if you're so clever. Go on, go on.
既然你这广隐明 乾脆你自己来试试看
Wingardium Leviosa.
温咖癌啦唯啊衣
Well done! See here, everyone, Miss Granger's done it!
表现得很好 大家快看，格兰休小姐成功了
Splendid!
好极了
Well done, dear.
表现得很好
I think we're going to need another feather over here.
抹烦再给我们一根羽毛，教授
"It's Leviosa, not Leviosar."
应该要强调 “啊”，而不是“荐^
She's a nightmare, honestly! No wonder she hasn't got any friends.
她实在是太诗人屡了 难怪束一个朋友也没有
I think she heard you.
好像被她区见了
Where's Hermione?
妙时呢?
Parvati said she wouldn't come out of the bathroom.
苑蒂说她把自己关在女生高所里
She said that she'd been in there all afternoon, crying.
艇在那里如了一整个下午
Troll in the dungeon!
地牢里有山怪!
Thought you ought to know.
我想应该通报你一声
Silence!
安静 !
Everyone will please not panic!
请大家不要懂继
Now...
现在…
...prefects will lead their house back to the dormitories.
各位级长 把自己学院的学生带回宕室
Teachers will follow me to the dungeons.
老师们跟我一起去地牢
Gryffindors, keep up, please, and stay alert.
萝来分多的学生，请跟上来 保持警戒
How could a troll get in?
山怪是怎么进来的?
Not on its own. Trolls are really stupid. Probably people playing jokes.
他不是自己进来的，山怪很策 可能是有人在昧作出
-What? -Hermione! She doesn't know.
-怎么啦? -妙棱还不知道山怪的事
I think the troll’s left the dungeon.
山怪好像克开地牢了
It’s going into the girls’ bathroom.
他朝女生高所走过去了
Hermione, move!
妙采，快跑啊 !
Help! Help!
救命啊 ! 救命啊 !
Hey, pea brain!
嘿，策瓜 !
Help!
救命啊 !
Do something!
快想办法
-What? -Anything!
-什么准法? -什么办法都行
-Hurry up! -Swish and flick.
-快点 ! -挥和强
Wingardium Leviosa.
温咖癌啦唯啊衣
Cool.
酷奖了
Is it dead?
他是不是死掉了?
I don't think so. Just knocked out.
好像还没死，只是香个而已
Troll boogers.
山怪鼻尿
Oh, my goodness! Explain yourselves, both of you!
我的天啊 请你们两位解释一下
-Well, what it is-- -It's my fault, Professor McGonagall.
一呵， 这是… -都是我不好，故教授…
Miss Granger?
格戎傈小姐?
I went looking for the troll. I thought I could handle it.
我跑去找山怪了 自以为对付得了他
But 1 was wrong.
但我错了
If Harry and Ron hadn't come and found me, I'd probably be dead.
要不是哈利和紫恩及时救了我 我搞不好就没命了
Be that as it may, it was an extremely foolish thing to do.
既然如此 你这种行为实在是太思奢了
l expected more rational behavior and am very disappointed in you.
我本来以为会理智一点 我对你很失望
Five points will be taken from Gryffindor...
萝来分多要被扣掉五分
...for your serious lack of judgment.
因为你严重缺乏判断力
As for you two gentlemen...
至苍你们两位…
...[ just hope you realize how fortunate you are.
你们的还所实在是太好了
Not many first-year students could take on a troll...
很少新生可以制伏成年山怪
...and live to tell the tale.
而且膛能活著回来
Five points...
五分…
... Will be awarded to each of you...
你们十位各加五分
...for sheer dumb luck.
只因为你们牌打正著
Perhaps you ought to go. It might wake up.
你们还是快走吧 山怪可能会醒过来
Take a bit of toast, mate. Go on.
吃点吐司吧，朋友
Ron's right. You'll need your strength today.
荣因说得对 你今天需要足锡的体力
I'm not hungry.
我不饿
Good luck today, Potter. You've proven yourself against a troll.
祝你好运，波特 你既然制傣了山怪…
A game of Quidditch should be easy work.
你地奇比赛应该准不合你
Even if it is against Slytherin.
就算对手是史莱哲林也扰妨
-That explains the blood. -Blood?
-难怪会有血 -血?
Last night, I'm guessing Snape let the troll in as a diversion...
我猜昨晚是石内下 把山怪放进来瑶东击西
...so he could get past that dog.
好趁机通过三头巨犬那一关
But he got bit, that’s why he’s limping.
结果印被咬了 所以走路才会一踊一踊的
But why would anyone go near that dog?
他堤嘛要接近那焦巨犬?
At Gringotts, Hagrid took something out of the vault.
我去古直阅那天 海格从金库里拿了一样东西
Said it was Hogwarts business, very secret.
他说那是埠格鞋兹的最高机密
That's what the dog's guarding. That's what Snape wants.
那是三头巨大在看守的东西 石内卜想把它偷到手
-Bit early for mail, isn't it? -But I never get mail.
-这刻早就收到邮包啊 -从来没人寄邮包给我
Let's open it.
拆天来看看
It's a broomstick.
是一把抬锅
That's not just a broomstick, it's a Nimbus 2000!
那不是普通的抬锅 那是光输两千
But who--?
到底是谁…，
-Scared, Harry? -A little.
-你会怕吗，哈利? -有一点
It's all right. 1 felt the same way before my first game.
没关俐 我第一次上场之前也有点怕
-What happened? -I don't really remember.
-结果呢? -我不太记得了
I took a Bludger to the head two minutes in.
没十分镀就被捕格打到
Woke up in hospital a week later.
在医院改迷一个星期才醒来
Welcome to Hogwarts’ first Quidditch game of the season.
炊迎各位观赏堆格桂兹 本李的第一场爸地奇比赛
Today's game, Slytherin versus Gryffindor!
今天是史莱哲林圣战葛来分多
The players take their positions...
玩手们各就各位
...as Madam Hooch steps onto the field to begin the game!
胡奇夫人上场准备开球
Now, I want a nice, clean game...
希望这会是场光明正大的比赛
..-from all of you!
大家都要遵守规则
The Bludgers are up, followed by the Golden Snitch.
搏格都坊起来了 接著是金探子
Remember, the Snitch is worth 150 points.
记住 抢到金探子可以得到1 5 0 分
The Seeker who catches the Snitch ends the game.
搜捕手一抢到金探子 比赛就宣告结束
The Quaffle is released and the game begins!
快浮放出了 比赛开始 !
Angelina Johnson scores! Ten points for Gryffindor!
莉娜得分了 葛来分多得了十分
Well done!
干得好 !
Slytherin takes the Quaffle. Bletchley passes to Captain Marcus Flint.
快浮落入史莱哲林手中 末里把捕格传给队长马科福林
Another 10 points to Gryffindor!
葛来分多又得了十分
Take that side!
守住那跟
What's going on with Harry's broomstick?
哈利的返需怎床啦?
It's Snape. He's jinxing the broom!
是石内上下，他在兰抬带下咒
-Jinxing the broom? What do we do? -Leave it to me.
-允抬需下史 ? 我们该怎庆办? -交给我吧
Come on, Hermione!
快点啊，妙起
Lacarnum Inflamarae.
拉卡隆依佛摩瑞
Fire! You're on fire!
著火了 ! 你身上著火了 !
Go, go, go, go!
加油，加油，加油…
Looks like he’s gonna be sick.
他好像快要吐了
He's got the Snitch!
他扒到金探子了
Harry Potter receives 150 points for catching the Snitch!
哈利波特抢到金探子 得到了1 5 0分
Gryffindor wins!
萝来分多多胶!
Nonsense! Why would Snape put a curse on Harry's broom?
胡说入道 石内卜干嘛诅咒哈利的抬姑?
Who knows? Why was he trying to get past that three-headed dog?
谁知道?9 为何他想通过三头巨大?9
-Who told you about Fluffy? -Aluffy?
-座告诉你毛毛的事? 一毛毛?了
-That thing has a name? -Of course he has a name. He's mine.
-那怪物还有名字啊? -当然有名字，他是我的狗
I bought him off an Irishman. I lent him to Dumbledore to guard--
我向一个爱尔兰人买的 和后来借给如不利多看守…
Shouldn't have said that. No more questions! That's top-secret.
不能说，别再问了
But whatever Fluffy’s guarding, Snape's trying to steal it.
但是，石内卜想偷毛毛看守的东西
Codswallop. Professor Snape is a Hogwarts teacher.
胡说入道 石内卜是违格革兹的老师
Teacher or not, 1 know a spell when I see one. I've read all about them.
不管他是不是老师，我一看就知道 他在下响，响语的书我都看过
You've got to keep eye contact, and Snape wasn't blinking.
限睛要紧盯著目标 石内让完全没版过限
Exactly.
就是这样
Now, you listen to me, all three of you.
你们三个都给我区好
You're meddling in things that ought hot to be meddled in. It’s dangerous.
这件事输不到你们来管 太和危险了
What that dog is guarding is between Dumbledore and Nicholas Flamel.
那焦狗看守的东西是 好不利多和尼乐勒梅的秘密
Nicholas Flamel?
尼乐勒梅?
I shouldn't have said that. I should not have said that.
我不小心说溜了踢
Nicholas Flamel. Who's Nicholas Flamel?
尼乐勒梅 尼乐勒梅是谁?
I don't know.
我不知道
Merry Christmas
耶诞快乐
Ring the Hogwart bell
敲约霍格鞋兹的饶
Cast a Christmas spell
侯个耶诞咒语
Knight to E-5.
骑士移到匡 5
Queen to E-5.
皇后移到刁 5
That's totally barbaric!
真野变
That's wizard’s chess. l see you've packed.
那是巫师棋 你打包好了
l see you haven't.
你没打包
Change of plans. My parents went to Romania to visit my brother Charlie.
计划改演了，我爸娟 要去路马尼亚找我哥哥查理
-He's studying dragons there. -Good. You can help Harry.
-他在那里研究龙 -好吧“，那你可以帮帮有哈利
He's going to the library to look up Nicholas Flamel.
他要去图书馆查尼乐勒梅的资料
We've looked a hundred times!
我们查过不下百次
Not in the restricted section. Happy Christmas.
禁书区还没查 耶诞快乐
I think we've had a bad influence on her.
她好像被我们带壤了
Harry, wake up! Come on, Harry, wake up!
哈利，醒一醒 ! 哈利，快醒醒 !
-Happy Christmas, Harry. -Happy Christmas, Ron.
-耶诞快乐，哈利 -阳诞快乐，莹思
What are you wearing?
你穿的是什么 ?
Oh, my mum made it. Looks like you've got one too.
我始织的毛衣 你好像也有一件
-'ve got presents? -Yeah.
-我有礼物? 一 对 可可
There they are.
在那逮
"Your father left this in my possession before he died.
这是你父亲栈死前留下的
It is time it was returned to you. Use it well.”
现在该交还给你了 好好使用吧,
-What is it? -Some kind of cloak.
-那是什么 ? -好像是斗德
Well, let's see, then. Put it on.
试穿看看
My body's gone!
我的身体不见了
I know what that is. That's an invisibility cloak!
我知道了，那是隐形斗禾
I'm invisible?
我隐形了吗?
They're really rare. l wonder who gave it to you.
这种斗公很罕见 是谁送给你的?
There was no name. It just said, "Use it well.”
没有署名 只襄好好使用
Famous Fire-Eaters. Fifteenth-Century Fiends.
知名香火人?7 “十五世纪恶魔“
Flamel. Nicholas Flamel. Where are you?
勒梅，尼乐勒梅 到底在哪里?
Who's there?
是座?
I know you're in there. You can't hide.
我知道你在里面 你躲不了的
Who is it? Show yourself.
是谁? 快出来
Severus, I....
石内卜，我…
You don’t want me as your enemy, Quirrell.
你不想和我为散吧，村车
-l don't know what you mean. -You know perfectly well what I mean.
-我不懂你的意思 -你心知肚明
We'll have another little chat soon.
有空再聊
When you've had time to decide where your loyalties lie.
先等你决定究竟要对谁效串
Professors. 1 found this in the restricted section.
十位教授 这是我在禁书区失到的
It's still hot. That means there's a student out of bed.
有学生偷溜下床了
Mum?
杂?
Dad?
和爸?
Ron, you've really gotta see this! Ron, you've gotta see this!
沫轧，你快来看啊
Ron, come on, get out of bed!
此思，快起床
-Why? -There's something you've got to see!
-干嘛? -你快来看
Come on! Come! Come look, it’s my parents!
快点啦，快点 你过来看，是我爸妈
I only see us.
我只看见我们俩
Look in properly. Go on, stand there.
这样不对，站过去那净
-There. You see them, don't you? -That's me! Only I'm head boy.
-好了，有没有看见他们? -那是我，我沁成级长了
And I'm holding the Quidditch Cup.
手里拿著魁地奇奖番
And bloody hell! I'm Quidditch captain too!
我也当上了魁地奇队长
Il look good.
我好威风
Harry, do you think this mirror shows the future?
哈利，这面镜子是显示未来吧?
How can it? Both my parents are dead.
怎订可能 ? 我爸妈都死了
Back again, Harry?
又回来了吗，哈利?
Il see that you, like many before you...
你和以前那些人一样
.. have discovered the delights of the Mirror of Erised.
都发现了意若思镜的乐趣
Il trust by now you realize what it does.
相信你已经知道镜子的功用了
Let me give you a clue.
我给你一点暗示
The happiest man on earth...
世上最快乐的人
...would look in the mirror and see only himself...
在镜中看到的…
...exactly as he is.
就是自己的真实面貌
So then, it shows us what we want. Whatever we want.
镜子反映出的是我们的答望吗? 所有的黎望吧?
Yes. And no.
对，也不对
It shows us nothing more or less...
镜子反映出的正是…
...than the deepest and most desperate desires of our hearts.
我们内心深处最渴望的事
Now you, Harry, who have never known your family...
哈利你没见通家人
...you see them standing beside you.
现在看到他们站在你身逮
But remember this, Harry.
但记住，哈利
This mirror gives us neither knowledge...
这面镜子不能提供我们知识…
or truth.
或真相
Men have wasted away in front of it. Even gone mad.
人们曾在镜子前虚据光队 其至因此而发疯
That is why tomorrow, it will be moved to a new home.
所以明天要把镜子搬去别的地方
And I must ask you...
请你干蕊…
... Not to go looking for it again.
别再来找这面镜子了
It does not do to dwell on dreams...
人不能活在萝里
..and forget to live.
而遗忘了现实生活
I had you looking in the wrong section. How could I be so stupid?
我害你们找错地方了 我怎么这记策?
I checked this out weeks ago for a bit of light reading.
这是我绑遇前借来消遣的书
This is light?
这算是消遗?9
Of course! Here it is!
当然吗，你们看
Nicholas Flamel is the only known maker of the Sorcerer's Stone.
尼乐勒梅是世上 唯一能出造出魔法石的人
The what?
抽造出什么 ?
Honestly, don't you two read?
真是的，你们平常不看书吗 ?
"The Sorcerer's Stone is a legendary substance with astonishing powers.
魔法石是一种传说中 具有和欧人魔力的石头
It'll transform any metal into pure gold...
能把金属变成纯金
...and produces the Elixir of Life which will make the drinker immortal.”
还能盘造长生不死药 喝了就能长生不死
-Immortal? -It means you'll never die.
-长生不死? -就是永下不会死
"The only Stone currently in existence belongs to Mr. Nicholas Flamel...
现存唯一的魔法石 是属尼乐勒梅先生所有
...the noted alchemist who last year celebrated his 665th birthday.”
他是著名的炼金衡士 去年蜀满6 6 5功
That's what Fluffy's guarding.
这就是毛毛在三楼看守的实物
That's what's under the trap door. The Sorcerer's Stone.
活板门底下藏的就是魔法石
Don't wish to be rude, but I'm in no state to entertain.
抱菊，不好意思 但我今天没心情玩
We know about the Sorcerer's Stone.
我们知道魔法石的事了
-We think Snape's trying to steal it. -Are you still on about him?
-石内卜想偷魔法石 -你们居然还在谈他?
We know he's after it. We don't know why.
他想偷魔法石 只是不知他为何要偷
Snape is one of the teachers protecting the Stone. He won't steal it.
五内卜可是保访魔法石的其中 一位老师，他才不会偷魔法石
What?
什么?
You heard. Come on, I'm a bit preoccupied today.
你贡清楚了 好了啦，我今天有点忙
Wait a minute. "One of the teachers"?
等一下 你列说其中一位老师?
There are other things defending the Stone, aren't there?
一定还有用别的方法 在保护魔法石对不对 ?
-Spells, enchantments. -Right.
-像是咒语啦、魔法啦 -对
Waste of bloody time, if you ask me.
但我觉得这是浪费时间
Ain't no one gonna get past Fluffy.
没人过得了毛毛那一天
Ain't a soul knows how, except for me and Dumbledore.
只有我和好不利多对付得了怨
I shouldn't have told you that. I should not have told you that.
我又不小心说溜了踢
-Hagrid, what exactly is that? -That? It's...
-海格，那是什么 ? -这是…
I know what that is!
我知道那是什么
But, Hagrid, how did you get one?
海格，你怎庆弄到的?
l won it. Off a stranger I met down at the pub.
我在酒吧壬 从陌生人手中赢来的
Seemed quite glad to be rid of it, as a matter of fact.
看来好像是个温手山芋
Is that...
那是…
..a dragon?
一焦龙吧 ?
That's not just a dragon. That's a Norwegian Ridgeback.
不只是龙，膛是挪威券人龙呢
My brother works with these in Romania.
我哥哥查理在中马尼亚研究龙
Isn't he beautiful? Oh, bless him. Look, he knows his mummy.
很漂亮吧? 了不起，独认识妈杂呢
Hello, Norbert.
哈唾，药萄
-Norbert? -He's gotta have a name, don't he?
-雍萄 ? -总得蔡籽取个名字
Don't you, Norbert?
对吧，药萄?
He'll have to be trained up a bit, of course.
凶要先受点训练才行
Who's that?
那是谁?
Malfoy.
马份
Oh, dear.
天哪
Hagrid always wanted a dragon. Told me so the first time 1 met him.
海格早就想养龙了 第一次见面时他就说了
It's crazy. And worse, Malfoy knows.
真荒唐 更灶的是被马份知道了
-l don't understand. Is that bad? -It's bad.
-我不懂，有那广灶吗?9 -灶透了
Good evening.
晚安
Nothing, I repeat, nothing...
扰论如何，我重桥一遍，扰论如何…
...gives a student the right to walk about at night.
学生都不能在半夜四处妃跑
Therefore, as punishment for your actions, 50 points will be taken.
我要惩罚你们的行为 扣五十分
-50?! -Each.
-五十分? -每个人
To ensure it doesn't happen again...
为了保证你们不会再犯
..-all four of you will receive detention.
悦你们四个人劳动服务
Excuse me, professor, perhaps I heard you wrong.
对不起，教授 可能是我匠错了
I thought you said the four of us.
你说的是“四个人”吗?
No, you heard me correctly.
你贡得没错
Honorable as your intentions were, you too were out of bed after hours.
可是你也在熄煤和后偷溜下床
You will join your classmates in detention.
你必须和他们一起接受处分
A pity they let the old punishments die.
可惜现在的处罚没以前最圭了
Was a time detention found you hanging by your thumbs in the dungeons.
以前在受罚的时候 会把你用拇指吊在地牢里
God, I miss the screaming.
天哪，真怀念那时候的惨叫声
You'll be serving detention with Hagrid tonight.
你们今晚要和海格 一起进行劳动服务
He's got a little job to do inside the Dark Forest.
要去黑和森林
A sorry lot, this, Hagrid.
你真个福，海格
Good God, you're not still on about that bloody dragon, are you?
天哪 你逮在为那焦龙的事生气吗?
Norbert’s gone.
药萄走了
Dumbledore sent him off to Romania to live in a colony.
如不利多把物送去路马尼亚 和其他同类一起住
That's good, isn't it? He's with his own kind.
这不是很好吗? 怨可以和同类在一起
What if he don't like Romania?
但他若不喜欢路马尼亚怎太办?
What if the other dragons are mean to him? He's only a baby.
如果别的龙对和忽不好呢? 怨村竟膛只是小宝宝
For God's sake, pull yourself together. You're going into the Forest.
拜旗，请你克制一下情绪 你逮要进森林内事呢
Got to have your wits about you.
到时候得全神贯注才行
The Forest? 1 thought that was a joke. We can't go in there.
森林 ? 我还以为是在天玩笑 那里是禁区
Students aren't allowed. And there are...
学生不能进去 那里有…
... werewolves.
狼人
There's more than werewolves in those trees.
森林里有的可不只是狼人
You can be sure of that.
这点倒是可以确定
Nighty-night.
晚安
Right. Let's go.
好了，我们走吧
Hagrid, what is that?
海格，那是什么?
What we're here for. See that?
这就是我们来的目的 看见没有?
That's unicorn blood, that is. I found one dead a few weeks ago.
那是独角软的血 我疙个礼拜前发现一具尾体
Now, this one’s been hurt bad by something.
这焦独角葡伤得很好重
So, it’s our job to go and find the poor beast.
所以我们的任务就是 找到那焦可屋的独角园
Ron, Hermione, come with me.
荣轧、妙杆，跟我来吧
And, Harry, you'll go with Malfoy.
哈利，你和轧份一组
Okay. Then I get Fang.
那我带牙牙一起去
Fine. Just so you know, he's a bloody coward.
好吧，不过你要小心 怨是个脆小抑
Wait till my father hears about this. This is servant's stuff.
要是被我爸匠到就惨了 这是偿人的工作
If 1 didn't know better, I'd say you were scared.
要是我没猜错的话 你显然是在害怕
I'm not scared, Potter.
我才不怕呢，波特
Do you hear that?
你区见没?
Come on, Fang.
走吧，牙牙
Scared!
害怕 !
What is it, Fang?
怎庆了，牙牙?
Harry Potter, you must leave. You are known to many creatures here.
哈利波特，你必须离开这壬 这里很多动物都认识你
The Forest is not safe at this time. Especially for you.
这时候的森林不太安全 你来这庄尤其危险
What was that thing you saved me from?
刚才要攻击我的是什么?
A monstrous creature. It is a terrible crime to slay a unicorn.
一焦怪物 负死独角园是润天大界
Drinking its blood will keep you alive even if you are an inch from death.
喝独角葡的血可以保住性命 就算垂死的人也救得回来
But at a terrible price. For you have slain something so pure...
但必须付出惨痛的代价 因为你负死的是纯党的生命
...that the moment the blood touches your lips, you will have a half-life.
从季的血碰触你的跑唇那一刻起 你就会演得半死不活
A cursed life.
挟有受诅咒的生命
-Who would choose such a life? -Can you think of no one?
-谁会想过这种生活呢? -你想不到是谁吗?
Do you mean to say that that thing that killed the unicorn...
你的意思是角死那焦独角炊…
...that was drinking its blood, that was Voldemort?
又喝陛的血的怪物 就是佛地魔吗?
Do you know what is hidden in the school at this very moment?
你知不知道此刻在学校里 藏了什么东西?
The Sorcerer's Stone.
魔法石
Harry!
哈利!
Hello there, Firenze. See you've met our young Mr. Potter.
你好啊，毕冷昔 看来你已经见过小波特了
You all right there, Harry?
你没事吧，哈利?
Harry Potter, this is where I leave you.
哈利波特，我们就在这里告别吧
You're safe now. Good luck.
你现在安全了“，祝你好运
You mean, You-Know-Who is out there right now in the Forest?
你是说那个人就在那里? 就在森林里 ?
But he’s weak. He's living off the unicorns.
可是他很处弱 只能千独角风的血维生
Don't you see? We had it wrong.
你们还不人懂吗 ? 我们猜错了
Snape doesn't want the Stone for himself. He wants it for Voldemort.
石内卜不是要把魔法石估为已有 他是要偷来上献给佛地魔
With the Elixir of Life, Voldemort will be strong again.
有了长生不死药 佛地魔又可以恢复力量了
He'll come back.
他膛会再回来报仇
But if he comes back...
他要是回来的话…
...you don't think he'll try to kill you, do you?
他该不会是想杀死你吧?
If he'd had the chance, he might have tried tonight.
如果被他还到机会 他说不定今晚就会来角我
And to think I've been worrying about my Potions final.
看我还在担心 魔于学的期末考呢
Hang on a minute. We're forgetting one thing.
等一下，我们忘了一件事
Who's the one wizard Voldemort always feared?
谁是佛地魔向来最怕的巫师?
Dumbledore. As long as Dumbledore is around, Harry, you're safe.
如不利多，只要有邮不利多在 哈利，你就不会有危险
As long as Dumbledore is around, you can't be touched.
只要用不利多在 就没人伤得了你
I'd heard Hogwarts’ final exams were frightful, but I found that enjoyable.
我以前就常邓人说堆格半兹的 期末考很鸡，可是我个党得很轻用
Speak for yourself. All right there, Harry?
只有才这麻觉得 你还好吧，哈利?
-My scar. It keeps burning. -It's happened before.
-我的疤痕一直痛得像火烧似的 -以前也发生过这种情况
-Not like this. -You should see the nurse.
-没这广痛过啊 -还是带你去找访士吧
I think it’s a warning. It means danger's coming.
我觉得这是一种警告 表示会有危险
-Of course! -What is it?
-没错 -怎和了?
Isn't it odd that what Hagrid wants more than anything is a dragon...
你们不觉得奇怪吗? 海格一直想养龙
..and a stranger just happens to have one?
突然就出现带著龙蛋的陌生人
How many people wander around with dragon eggs?
有多少人会带著龙蛋 到处走动 ?
Why didn't I see it before?
我怎庆没早点想到呢?
Who gave you the egg? What did he look like?
那个龙蛋是谁给你的? 他长什么样子?
I never saw his face. He kept his hood up.
我没看清楚他的脸 他一直用斗禾遮车
You and this stranger must have talked.
你有和这个陌生人交谈过吧?
He wanted to know what sort of creatures I looked after.
他问我饲养台哪些动物
I said, "After Fluffy, a dragon's gonna be no problem.”
我告诉他 : 状了毛毛以后 就算养龙也绝对不成问题
-Was he interested in Fluffy? -Of course he was interested.
-他对毛毛很有惧趣吗? -他当然对毛毛很感机趣
How often do you come across a three-headed dog?
又不是到处都看得到三头巨大
But I told him, "The trick with any beast is to know how to calm him.”
可是我告诉他副服野葡的入读 就是想法子让和籽镇定下来
Take Fluffy, for example. Play him music and he falls straight to sleep.
就拿毛毛来说吧，演奏音乐给和贡 怨马上就会睡著了
I shouldn't have told you that.
我又说溜了跑
Where are you going?
你们要去哪里?
We have to see Dumbledore. Immediately!
我们要找几不利多教授 事不宜还 !
I'm afraid he's not here.
如不利多教授不在这壬
He received an urgent owl from the Ministry of Magic and left.
魔法部派猫头魔送急件给他 他就立刻启程前往偷敦
He's gone? But this is important!
他真的走了吗? 可是我们有要和涌的事
This is about the Sorcerer's Stone!
是关於魔法石
-How do you know--? -Someone's going to try and steal it.
-你们怎庆会知道… -有人想偷走魔法石
I don't know how you know, but I assure you it is well protected.
我不知道你们怎床晓得魔法石的事 不过它很安全
Now would you go back to your dormitories? Quietly.
快回去寝室吧 催量别出融
That was no stranger Hagrid met. It was Snape.
海格在村子里遇到的不是陌生人 那个人是石内下
Which means he knows how to get past Fluffy.
他知道怎样通过毛毛那一关了
-And with Dumbledore gone-- -Good afternoon.
-好不利多又不在… -午安
What would three young Gryffindors...
你们三个葛来分多学院的小朋友
...be doing inside on a day like this?
天所这广好，怎订没出去玩?
-We were just-- -You ought to be careful.
-我们只是在… -你们要小心一点
People will think you're...
别人可能会以为…
...up to something.
你们在打什么壤主意
We go down the trap door. Tonight.
我们从活板门下去 今天晚上就去
Trevor.
吹宣
Trevor, go! You shouldn't be here!
吹宝 ! 快走吧，你不应该来这里
Neither should you. You're sneaking out again, aren't you?
你们也不应该来 你们又要偷溜出来了，对吧?
-Neville, listen. We were-- -No, I won't let you!
-奈威，避我说，我们… -不行，我不准你们去
You'll get Gryffindor into trouble again. Il fight you.
萝来分多学院会被你们害惨的 我会打你们的
Neville, I'm really sorry about this. Petrificus Totalus.
奈威，真的很对不起 整整化石
You're a little scary sometimes, you know that?
你有时候绝可怕的 和知道吗?
Brilliant, but scary.
很属害，不过很可怕
Let's go.
我们走吧
-Sorry. -It's for your own good, you know.
-对不起 -这样做是为了你好
-You stood on my foot! -Sorry.
-你踩到我的脚了 -对不起
Alohomora.
阿洛哈姆啦
Wait a minute. He's...
等一下，季…
. ... Snoring.
在打英
Snape's already been here. He's put a spell on the harp.
石内上下已经来了 他对登玲下了加
It's got horrible breath.
凶的嘴巴好鼻
-We have to move its paw. -What?
-必须把怨的脚掌移并 -什么?
Come on!
快来 !
Okay. Push.
好了“，用力推
I'll go first. Don't follow until l give you a sign.
我先走，等我发信号再跟过来
If something bad happens, get yourselves out.
要是情况不妙 你们就自己逃命吧
Does it seem a bit quiet to you?
你们有没有党得好安静了?
The harp.
登参
It's stopped playing.
登琴没有演奏了
Jump!
焉啊!
Lucky this plant thing's here, really.
幸好有这株植物抽住
Stop moving, both of you. This is Devil's Snare.
你们傅别再乱动了 这是魔鬼网
You have to relax. If you don't, it will only kill you faster.
你们别太紧张 要不然就会死得更快
Kill us faster? Oh, now I can relax!
死得更快? 这下子我就不树张了
Hermione!
妙起!
-Now what are we gonna do? -Just relax!
-现在该怎入只? -只管放轻朋
-Hermione, where are you? -Do what I say! Trust me.
-妙朴，人在哪里?了 -照著我的话做 ! 相信我
-Are you okay? -Yeah, I'm fine.
-你没事吧? -没事，我很好
-He's not relaxing, is he? -Apparently not.
-他没放去颖，对吧? -显然没有
-We've gotta do something. -What?
-一定要想个办法 -什么准法?
l remember reading something in Herbology.
还记得我在药草学的书上看过
Devil's Snare, Devil's Snare. It's deadly fun...
魔鬼网，魔多网 它会致人於死
..-but will sulk in the sun! That's it! It hates sunlight.
可是焉到阳光就完蛋了 对了，恶魔网讨灰阳光
Lumus Solem.
煤迷光
-Ron, you okay? -Yeah.
-此轧，你没事吧? -没事
Lucky we didn't panic.
幸好我们没移慌失措
Lucky Hermione pays attention in Herbology.
幸好妙肝上药草学课时很认真
What is that?
那是什么声音 ?
I don’t know. Sounds like wings.
我不知道，好像是翅膀挥动的声音
Curious. I've never seen birds like these.
真奇怪，我没看过这种饥
They're not birds. They're keys.
那不是高，是锭于
And I'll bet one of them fits that door.
一定有把给是可以打开那局站
-What's this all about? -l don’t know.
-这是怎庆回事? -我不知道
Strange.
真奇怪
Alohomora!
阿洛哈姆啦
Well, it was worth a try.
试试看也扰妨
What will we do? There must be a thousand keys.
现在怎庆办? 那里有上千把给是
We want a big, old-fashioned one. Probably rusty.
我们要找的是一把老式大锭是 可能像门把一样生铺了
I see it! The one with the broken wing.
我看到了 翅膀受伤的那把给是
What's wrong?
怎庆呢，哈利?
It's too simple.
这太不费吹灰之力了
Go on! If Snape could catch it on that old broomstick, you can.
去吧，如果石内卜用善返锅追得上它 那你也办得到
You're the youngest Seeker in a century.
你可是百年来最年轻的搜捕手
This complicates things a bit.
事情伙得有点复杂了
Catch the key!
抓住那把欠王
Hurry up!
快点 !
I don't like this. I don't like this at all.
我觉得不太对劲 实在是太不对劲了
Where are we? A graveyard.
这是哪里?墓地?
This is no graveyard.
这才不是墓地
It's a chessboard.
这是西洋棋盘
There's the door.
门在那里
Now what do we do?
现在怎庆办?
It's obvious, isn't it? We've got to play our way across the room.
不是很明显吗? 要下棋才能通过这个房间
Harry, you take the empty bishop's square.
哈利，你站在主教那个空格里
Hermione, you'll be the queen-side castle.
妙导，炼就当皇后劣簿的城堡吧
As for me, I'll be a knight.
至分我，我来当骑士
What happens now?
现在呢?
Well, white moves first.
嗯，白棋先移动
... we play.
换我们出招了
Ron, you don't suppose this is going to be like...
上思，你该不会以为真的是在玩…
...real wizard's chess, do you?
巫师西洋棋吧?
You there, D-5.
你移到D 5
Yes, Hermione.
对，妙果
I think this is gonna be exactly like wizard'’s chess.
我觉得这和巫师西洋棋 完全一模一样
Castle to E-4!
城堡移到刁 4
Pawn to C-3!
雁子移到C 3
-Wait a minute. -You understand right, Harry.
-等一下 -你明白了吧“，哈利
Once I make my move, the queen will take me.
只要我一移动 皇后就会把我吃掉
Then you're free to check the king.
这样你就可以趁机进攻国王
-No. Ron, no! -What is it?
-紫思 ! 不行啊 ! -怎和了?
-He's going to sacrifice himself. -No, there must be another way!
-他要竹牲自己 -不行，一定还有别的办法
Do you wanna stop Snape from getting that Stone or not?
你到底想不想 阻赴石内卜偷走魔法石?
Harry, it's you that has to go on. I know it.
哈利，你必须继续前进 我觉得该去的人…
Not me. Not Hermione. You.
不是我，不是妙采，而是你
Knight to H-3.
骑士移到百 3
Check.
将军
Ron!
沫因 !
No, don't move! Don't forget, we're still playing.
不 !别筷支 别忘了我们还在下棋
Checkmate.
将军
Take care of Ron. Then go to the owlery.
好好照闯本思 然后去找和猎头麻
Send a message to Dumbledore. Ron's right.
寄封信给性不利多 荣因说得对
I have to go on.
我必须继续前进
You'll be okay, Harry. You're a great wizard. You really are.
你不会有事的，哈利 你是伟大的魔法师，我真的这麻党得
Not as good as you.
我才比不上炼呢
Me? Books and cleverness. There are more important things.
我?我只是千书本和小隐明 但还有些更重要的条件
Friendship and bravery. And, Harry, just be careful.
友党和勇气 哈利，你要小心一点
You?
是你?
No, it can't be. Snape, he was the--
不，不可能 石内卜，他才是…
Yes, he does seem the type, doesn't he?
对，他看起来一脸壤相对吧 ?
Next to him, who would suspect...
有他在身超，谁退会怀疑…
...poor, stuttering Professor Quirrell?
口吃的村车教授?
But that day, during the Quidditch match, Snape tried to kill me.
可是魁地奇比赛那天 石内卜还想害死我
No, dear boy. I tried to kill you!
你错了，亲党的孩子 想角你的人是我
If Snape’s cloak hadn't caught fire and broken my eye contact...
要不是石内让的斗禾著了火 客得我没准法死盯著你
...l would have succeeded.
我早就成功了
Even with Snape muttering his countercurse.
石内卜叭再多解响话也没用
Snape was trying to save me?
石内卜想救我?
I knew you were a danger to me, especially after Halloween.
我一开始就看出你会威萌到我 尤其是在蕊村和节过和后
-Then you let the troll in! -Very good, Potter, yes.
-所以是你把山怪放人进来的 -算你属害，波特，答对了
Snape, unfortunately, wasn't fooled.
可惜石内卜没上我的当
While everyone ran about, he went to the third floor to head me off.
其他人都在地牢里四处乱窜 他分跑去三楼想拉住我
He, of course, never trusted me again.
当然他再也不会相信我了
He rarely left me alone. But he doesn’t understand.
他烙乎不让我一个人独处 只是他没搞清楚
I'm never alone. Never.
我从来都不是一个人
Now, what does this mirror do?
这面镜子是干嘛用的?
l see what I desire.
我能看到自己想要的东西
Il see myself holding the Stone. But how do I get it?
我看到自己手里拿著魔法石 可是我是怎床拿到的 ?
Use the boy.
利用那个男孩
Come here, Potter! Now!
给我明来，波特 ! 快点 !
Tell me, what do you see?
告诉我，你看见了什么 ?
What is it? What do you see?
你看见了什么 ?
I'm shaking hands with Dumbledore. I've won the house cup.
我在和好不利多握手 我赢得了学院番冠军
He lies.
他说议
Tell the truth! What do you see?
跟我说实话，你看见了什么?
-Let me speak to him. -Master, you are not strong enough.
-让我和他谈谈 -主人，你还没恢复力量
I have strength enough for this.
我的力量足以应付得了
Harry Potter...
哈利波特…
...we meet again.
我们又见面了
Voldemort.
佛地魔
Yes. You see what I've become?
没错，看到我现在的模样了吧?
See what I must do to survive?
你知道我要怎样求生了吧?
Live off another. A mere parasite.
靠别人活下去，活像是个寄生串
Unicorn blood can sustain me...
独角葡的血可以让我延绩生命
...but it cannot give me a body of my own.
但钾拓法让我得到自己的身体
But there is something that can.
不过还有别的办法
Something that, conveniently enough, lies in your pocket.
那件垂手可得的东西 就在你的口袋里
Stop him!
阻止他 !
Don't be a fool.
别傻了
Why suffer an horrific death...
你可以和我一起活下去
...when you can join me and live?
又何必冒险惨死史?
Never!
休想 !
Bravery. Your parents had it too.
真勇敢，你爸杂也很勇敢
Tell me, Harry...
告诉我，哈利…
...-would you like to see your mother and father again?
想不想再见到你爸杂?
Together...
只要我们合作…
...we can bring them back.
就能让他们起死回生
All 1 ask is for something in return.
我只要求一样东西作为回报
That's it, Harry.
面对现实吧，哈利
There is no good and evil.
世上痊没有绝对的善与黔
There is only power...
差别只是在於强者…
..and those too weak to seek it.
和和扰法认清事实的弱者之分
Together, we'll do extraordinary things.
只要我们合作 一定能有非凡的成就
Just give me the Stone!
把魔法石交给我
You liar!
你这个驴子
Kill him!
角了他
-What is this magic? -Fool, get the Stone!
-这是什么魔法? -白弟 ! 快去拿魔法石
Good afternoon, Harry.
午安，哈利
-Tokens from your admirers? -Admirers?
-这是仰慕者送你的礼物吗 ? -你幕者?
What happened in the dungeons between you and Professor Quirrell is a secret.
你和村若教授在地牢里的事 必须完全保密
So, naturally, the whole school knows.
所以全校师生自然全都知道了
l see that your friend Ronald has saved you the trouble...
看来你那位朋友莹思替你省了…
...of opening your Chocolate Frogs.
拆开巧克力圣的麻烦
Ron was here? Is he all right? What about Hermione?
柴思也在? 他没事吧? 妙时呢?
Fine. They're both just fine.
没事，他们俩都安然无意
-What happened to the Stone? -Relax, dear boy.
-但那魔法石呢? -别紧张，我亲党的孩子
The Stone has been destroyed.
魔法石已经被摧毁了
My friend Nicholas and I have had a little chat...
我和好友尼乐聊了一会儿
..and agreed it was best all around.
我们认为这是最妥善的做法
But then, Flamel, he'll die, won't he?
不过尼乐勒梅就会死吐?
He has enough Elixir to set his affairs in order.
他还存了些长生不死药 锡他们把事情安排妥当
But yes, he will die.
不过没错，他终究还是会死
How is it 1 got the Stone, sir?
魔法石怎订会落到我手上?
One minute I was staring in the mirror and--
原本我还在看著镜子，突然就…
You see, only a person...
你还不明白唉?任何人…
...who wanted to find the Stone, find it...
只有真心想找到魔法石
...but not use it, would be able to get it.
而不是存心要拿来用的人 才能得到魔法石
That is one of my more brilliant ideas.
这是我想出来的好方法
And between you and me, that is saying something.
别说出去，不过 我这方法实在太好了
Does that mean, with the Stone gone, that Voldemort can never come back?
这表示魔法石消失以和后 佛地魔就再也不能回来了吗 ?
I'm afraid...
恐怕…
...there are ways in which he can return.
他还是有内法再回来
Harry, do you know why...
哈利，你知道对洛教授…
...Professor Quirrell couldn't bear to have you touch him?
为什么受不了你碰触他吗?
It was because of your mother. She sacrificed herself for you.
那是因为你母亲的缘故 她为了你煌牲了自己
And that kind of act leaves a mark.
这类举动会留下了一个印记
No, this kind of mark cannot be seen.
不对，这种印记是看不见的
-It lives in your very skin. -What is it?
-它存留在你的皮广上 -什么印记?
Love, Harry. Love.
就是过啊，哈利
Bertie Bott’s Every Flavor Beans.
柏蒂的全口味豆子
l was most unfortunate in my youth to come across a vomit-flavored one.
我小时候不幸的吃到 一颗味道很吐心的豆子
And since then, I've lost my liking for them.
和后来就再也不敢吃了
But I think I could be safe...
可是我想应该可以选颗…
...with a nice toffee.
太妃糖口味的
Alas!
天哪
Earwax.
是耳尿口味的
-All right there, Ron? -All right. You?
-你还好吧，生思? -我很好，你呢?
All right. Hermione?
我很好，妙里呢?
Never better.
好得不得了
Another year gone.
又一年过去了
And now, as I understand it, the house cup needs awarding.
现在就我所知 我们该来颁发学院冠军番了
And the points stand thus:
各学院的分数如下…
In fourth place, Gryffindor with 312 points.
第四名 萝来分多，3 工2分
Third place, Hufflepuff with 352 points.
第三名 赫夫帕夫，352分
In second place...
第二名…
...Ravenclaw with 426 points.
雷文克劳，4 2 6分
And in first place...
第一名…
.. with 472 points, Slytherin house.
得分是4了2分，史莱哲林学院
Nice one, mate.
干得好
Yes, well done, Slytherin. Well done.
表现得很好，史莱哲林 表现得很好
However, recent events must be taken into account.
不过 最近有光件事也必须列入考量
And I have a few last-minute points to award.
最后还要再加几分
To Miss Hermione Granger, for the cool use of intellect...
妙林格戎像小姐 在其他人陷入重大危难时…
... while others were in grave peril...
冷静地运用智慧有辽困
...50 points.
加五十分
Good job.
干得好
Second, to Mr. Ronald Weasley, for the best-played game of chess...
其次是此因本斯理先生 最优秀的西洋棋手
...that Hogwarts has seen these many years, 50 points.
霍格革兹多年来无人能出其右 加五十分
And third...
再来是…
...to Mr. Harry Potter...
哈利波特先生
...for pure nerve and outstanding courage...
腾识台人，勇气可嘉
...l award Gryffindor house 60 points.
我再加给葛来分多学院六十分
We're tied with Slytherin!
我们和史菜哲林同分了
Finally, it takes a great deal of bravery to stand up to your enemies...
最和后，要捍身而出对抗散人 的确需要很大的勇气
...but a great deal more to stand up to your friends.
但若是要捍身反抗朋友 估需要更大的勇气
l award 10 points...
我再加十分…
...to Neville Longbottom.
给奈威隆巴屯
Assuming that my calculations are correct...
如果我计算得没错…
... 1 believe that a change of decoration is in order.
这里的装饰要改变一下了
Gryffindor wins the house cup.
萝来分多赢得学院番冠军
Come on, now. Hurry up, you'll be late.
动作快，你们快来不及了
Train's leaving. Go on. Come on, hurry up.
火车要开了“，快走吧 动作快一点
-Come on, Harry. -One minute.
-快点啊，哈利 -等一下
Thought you were leaving without saying goodbye, did you?
连声再见也不说就想走啦?
Thanks, Hagrid.
谢谢你，海格
Go on. On with you. On with you now. Oh, listen, Harry.
去吧，快去啊 聘我说，哈利…
If that dolt of a cousin of yours, Dudley, gives you any grief...
如果你那个策蛋表哥于力 再敢敬负你
..-you could always threaten him...
你就骑距他…
...with a nice pair of ears to go with his tail.
说要送他一对猪耳条 好搭配他那休和猪尾巴
But we're not allowed to do magic away from Hogwarts. You know that.
可是我们一龊并惟格革兹 就不能用魔法了，这你也晓得
I do. But your cousin don't, do he?
我是晓得，但你表哥可不晓得
Feels strange to be going home, doesn't it?
要回家了“，感党很奇怪吧?
I'm not going home.
我又不是真的要回家
Not really.
那才不是我的家呢